Finding Aid for Lutheran Church in America, Michigan Synod records, 1917-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Lutheran Church in America, Michigan Synod records
1917-1987
Lutheran Church in America. Michigan Synod.
86802 Ba 2; BA Outsize; UBAl
President's correspondence, executive committee minutes, and minutes of annual conventions; also files on individual churches in the Synod, including clippings, reports, church histories and programs; and photographs.
42 linear feet in 46 boxes
2 oversize volumes
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was deposited by the Michigan Synod, Lutheran Church in America (Donor No. 5738 ) in August 1975. Periodic additions have been received since then.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Lutheran Church in America was formed from the merger in 1962 of four Lutheran groups: the United Lutheran Church in America, the Augustana Evangelical Lutheran Church, the American Evangelical Lutheran Church, and the Finnish Evangelical Lutheran Church. In 1988, the LCA merged with the American Lutheran Church and the much smaller Association of Evangelical Lutheran Churches to form the Evangelical Lutheran Church in America.
The first annual convention of the Michigan Synod was held in Detroit in June 1920.
The records of the Michigan Synod of the Lutheran Church in America include president's correspondence; executive committee minutes; and minutes of annual conventions; files on individual churches in the Synod, including clippings, reports, church histories and programs; and photographs. The records have been arranged into the following series: Organizational and Administrative Records; Archivist's files; Organizational units and programs; Lutheran Church Women; Printed material; Church files; Topical files; and Visual Materials. Most of the records prior to 1962 originally came from the archives of United Lutheran Church in America.
Subjects:
Abiding Presence Lutheran Church (Rochester, Mich.); Adoration Lutheran Church (Bay City, Mich.); Advent Evangelical Lutheran Church (East Detroit, Mich.); Advent Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); All Saints Evangelical Lutheran Church (East Detroit, Mich.); All Saints Lutheran Church (Mason, Mich.); Antioch Lutheran Church (Farmington, Mich.); Ascension Lutheran Church (Flint, Mich.); Ascension Lutheran Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.); Augsburg Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Augustana Lutheran Church (Tustin, Mich.); Augustana Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Bethany Lutheran Church (Kaleva, Mich.); Bethany Lutheran Church (Ludington, Mich.); Bethany Lutheran Church (Roseville, Mich.); Bethel Lutheran Church (Cedarville, Mich.); Bethlehem Lutheran Church (Mount Clemens, Mich.); Bethlehem Lutheran Church (Traverse City, Mich.); Bethel Evangelical Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Bethlehem Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Bethlehem Lutheran Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.); Calvary Evangelical Lutheran Church (Clarkston, Mich.); Calvary Lutheran Church (Southfield, Mich.); Central Lutheran Church (Muskegon, Mich.); Christ Evangelical Lutheran Church (Monroe, Mich.); Christ Lutheran Church (Waterford, Mich.); Christ of the Lakes Lutheran Church (Pontiac, Mich.); Christ Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Christ of the Redeemer Lutheran Church (Adrian, Mich.); Christ the King Evangelical Lutheran Church (Livonia, Mich.); Church of the Cross Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Cross of Glory Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Dannebrog Lutheran Church (Greenville, Mich.); Divinity Lutheran Church (Warren, Mich.); Emanuel Lutheran Church (Ludington, Mich.); Evangelical Lutheran Church of the Resurrection (Detroit, Mich.); Epiphany Lutheran Church (Plymouth, Mich.); Evangelical Lutheran Church of the Resurrection (Saginaw, Mich.); Evangelical Lutheran Church of the Transfiguration (Taylor, Mich.); Faith Lutheran Church (Saline, Mich.); First English Lutheran Church (South Haven, Mich.); First English Lutheran Church (Southgate, Mich.); First Lutheran Church (Montcalm County, Mich.); Faith Lutheran Church (Flat Rock, Mich.); Faith Lutheran Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.); First Hungarian Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Gethsemane Lutheran Church (Berkley, Mich.); Gethsemane Lutheran Church (Wyoming, Mich.); Gloria Dei Evangelical Lutheran Church (Tecumseh, Mich.); Gloria Dei Lutheran Church (Pontiac, Mich.); Good Shepherd Lutheran Church (Manistee, Mich.); Good Shepherd Lutheran Church (Monroe, Mich.); Good Shepherd Lutheran Church (Redford, Mich.); Gloria Dei Evangelical Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Good Hope Lutheran Church (Garden City, Mich.); Good Shepherd Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Grace Lutheran Church (Albion, Mich.); Grace Lutheran Church (Alpena, Mich.); Grace Lutheran Church (East Tawas, Mich.); Grace Lutheran Church (Lansing, Mich.); Holy Communion Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Holy Cross Evangelical Lutheran Church (Ionia, Mich.); Holy Cross Evangelical Lutheran Church (Livonia, Mich.); Holy Trinity Lutheran Church (Flint, Mich.); Holy Trinity Slovak Evangelical Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Holy Cross Lutheran Church (Westland, Mich.); Holy Redeemer Lutheran Church (Southgate, Mich.); Holy Spirit Church (West Bloomfield, Mich.); Holy Spirit Lutheran Church (Orchard Lake, Mich.); Holy Trinity Lutheran Church (Niles, Mich.); Hope Lutheran Church (Marlette, Mich.); Hope Lutheran Church (Oscoda, Mich.); Hope Lutheran Church (Dearborn, Mich.); Hope Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Immanuel Lutheran Church (Allegan, Mich.); Immanuel Lutheran Church (Big Rapids, Mich.); Immanuel Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Immanuel Lutheran Church (Jackson, Mich.); Incarnate Word Lutheran Church (Bloomfield Hills, Mich.); Jehovah Evangelical Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Jefferson Avenue Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Juhl, Zion, Trinity Lutheran Parish (Marlette, Mich.); King of Kings Lutheran Church (Lake Orion, Mich.); Luther Memorial Evangelical Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Lebanon Evangelical Lutheran Church (Whitehall, Mich.); Lebanon Lutheran Church (Muskegon, Mich.); Lutheran Church in America. Michigan Synod.; Lutheran Church (Mount Hope, Mich.); Lutheran Church (Olivet, Mich.); Lutheran Church of the Apostles (Belleville, Mich.); Lutheran Church of the Ascension (Pontiac, Mich.); Lutheran Church of the Master (Troy, Mich.); Lutheran Church (Berrien Springs, Mich.); Lutheran Church (Grand Haven, Mich.); Lutheran Church in America. Michigan Synod.; Lutheran Church--Michigan.; Lutheran Church of the Atonement (Detroit, Mich.); Lutheran Church of the Incarnation (Farmington, Mich.); Lutheran Church of the Reformation (Detroit, Mich.); Lutheran Church of Our Risen Lord (Flint, Mich.); Mamrelund Lutheran Church (Kent City, Mich.); Messiah Lutheran Church (Bay City, Mich.); Messiah Lutheran Church (Constantine, Mich.); Messiah Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Messiah Lutheran Church (Manistee, Mich.); Moore Park Lutheran Church (Saint Joseph County, Mich.); Mt. Hope Lutheran Church (Marshall, Mich.); Nativity Evangelical Lutheran Church (Roseville, Mich.); Northwest Emmanuel Evangelical Lutheran Church (Southfield, Mich.); Olivet Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Our Saviour Evangelical Lutheran Church (Manistee, Mich.); Our Saviour Lutheran Church (Saginaw, Mich.); Our Redeemer Lutheran Church (Kalamazoo, Mich.); Peace Evangelical Lutheran Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Peace Lutheran Church (Charlotte, Mich.); Prince of Peace Lutheran Church (Dearborn, Mich.); Prince of Peace Lutheran Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.); Prince of Glory Evangelical Lutheran Church (Madison Heights, Mich.); Redemption Lutheran Church (Orchard Lake, Mich.); Resurrection Lutheran Church (Saginaw, Mich.); Redeemer Lutheran Church (Lansing, Mich.); Reformation Lutheran Church (Coldwater, Mich.); St. Andrew's Lutheran Church (Birmingham, Mich.); St. James Lutheran Church (Jackson, Mich.); St. John's Evangelical Lutheran Church (Baroda, Mich.); St. John's Evangelical Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. John's Lutheran Church (Grayling, Mich.); St. John's Lutheran Church (Lake City, Mich.); St. Mark's Lutheran Church (Benton Harbor, Mich.); St. Matthew Lutheran Church (Allen Park, Mich.); St. Paul's Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Paul's Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Paul's Lutheran Church (Grandville, Mich.); St. Peter's German and Saxon Evangelical Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Peter's Lutheran Church (Battle Creek, Mich.); St. Peter's Danish Evangelical Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Philip's Workers Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Stephen Evangelical Lutheran Church (Lansing, Mich.); St. Thomas Lutheran Church (Grosse Ile, Mich.); St. John's Evangelical Lutheran Church (Three Rivers, Mich.); St. John's Lutheran Church (Sidney, Mich.); St. Luke's Lutheran Church (Muskegon, Mich.); St. Luke's Lutheran Church (Stevensville, Mich.); St. Michael Lutheran Church (Plymouth, Mich.); St. Paul's Lutheran Church (Temperance, Mich.); St. Philip Lutheran Church (Trenton, Mich.); St. Philip's Lutheran Church (Ypsilanti, Mich.); St. Stephen Evangelical Lutheran Church (Warren, Mich.); St. Stephen Lutheran Church (Rockford, Mich.); St. Thomas Lutheran Church (Sterling Heights, Mich.); St. Timothy Evangelical Lutheran Church (Oak Park, Mich.); St. Timothy Lutheran Church (Midland, Mich.); St. Timothy Lutheran Church (Sturgis, Mich.); Samaria Lutheran Church (Ypsilanti, Mich.); Samuel Lutheran Church (Muskegon, Mich.); Saron Lutheran Church (Saint Joseph, Mich.); Settlement Lutheran Church (Gowen, Mich.); Shepherd of the Lakes Lutheran Church (Walled Lake, Mich.); Salem Lutheran Church (Flint, Mich.); Transfiguration Lutheran Church (Fenton, Mich.); Trinity Lutheran Church (Manton, Mich.); Trinity Lutheran Church (Mottville, Mich.); Triumphant Cross Lutheran Church (Saint Clair Shores, Mich.); Trinity Evangelical Lutheran Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Trinity Evangelical Lutheran Church (Hillsdale, Mich.); Trinity Evangelical Lutheran Church (Kalamazoo, Mich.); Trinity Lutheran Church (Battle Creek, Mich.); Trinity Lutheran Church (Brown City, Mich.); Trinity Lutheran Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.); Trinity Lutheran Church (Greenville, Mich.); Unity Evangelical Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Unity Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.); Victory-Trinity Lutheran Church (Ludington, Mich.); Zion Lutheran Church (Cadillac, Mich.); Zion Lutheran Church (Le Roy, Mich.); Adrian (Mich.); Albion (Calhoun County, Mich.); Allegan (Mich.); Allen Park (Mich.); Alpena (Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.); Baroda (Mich.); Battle Creek (Mich.); Bay City (Mich.); Benton Harbor (Mich.); Berkley (Mich.); Berrien Springs (Mich.); Big Rapids (Mich.); Birmingham (Mich.); Bloomfield Hills (Mich.); Brown City (Mich.); Cadillac (Mich.); Charlotte (Mich.); Clarkston (Mich.); Coldwater (Mich.); Constantine (Mich.); Dearborn (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.); Eastpointe (Mich.); East Tawas (Mich.); Farmington (Mich.); Fenton (Mich.); Flat Rock (Mich.); Flint (Mich.); Garden City (Mich.); Gowen (Mich.); Grand Haven (Mich.); Grand Rapids (Mich.); Grandville (Mich.); Grayling (Mich.); Greenville (Mich.); Grosse Ile (Mich.); Hillsdale (Mich.); Ionia (Mich.); Jackson (Mich.); Kalamazoo (Mich.); Kaleva (Mich.); Kent City (Mich.); Lake City (Mich.); Lake Orion (Mich.); Lansing (Mich.); Le Roy (Mich.); Livonia (Mich.); Ludington (Mich.); Madison Heights (Mich.); Manistee (Mich.); Manton (Mich.); Marlette (Mich.); Marshall (Mich.); Mason (Mich.); Midland (Mich.); Monroe (Mich.); Montcalm County (Mich.); Mottville (Mich.); Mount Clemens (Mich.); Mount Hope (Mich.); Muskegon (Mich.); Niles (Mich.); Oak Park (Mich.); Olivet (Mich.); Orchard Lake (Mich.); Oscoda (Mich.); Plymouth (Mich.); Pontiac (Mich.); Rochester (Mich.); Roseville (Mich.); Saginaw (Mich.); Saint Clair Shores (Mich.); Saint Joseph (Mich.); Saint Joseph County (Mich.); Saline (Mich.); Sidney (Mich.); Southfield (Mich.); Southgate (Mich.); Sterling Heights (Mich.); Stevensville (Mich.); Sturgis (Mich.); Taylor (Mich.); Tecumseh (Mich.); Temperance (Mich.); Three Rivers (Mich.); Traverse City (Mich.); Trenton (Mich.); Troy (Mich.); Tustin (Mich.); Walled Lake (Mich.); Warren (Mich.); Waterford (Mich.); Westland (Mich.); Whitehall (Mich.); Wyoming (Mich.); Ypsilanti (Mich.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Adrian (Mich.)--Churches.; Albion (Calhoun County, Mich.)--Churches.; Alcona (Mich.)--Churches.; Algonac (Mich.)--Churches.; Allen Park (Mich.)--Churches.; Alma (Mich.)--Churches.; Alpena (Mich.)--Churches.; Amelith (Mich.)--Churches.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Churches.; Armada (Mich.)--Churches.; Au Gres (Mich.)--Churches.; Auburn (Mich.)--Churches.; Bad Axe (Mich.)--Churches.; Battle Creek (Mich.)--Churches.; Bay City (Mich.)--Churches.; Benton Harbor (Mich.)--Churches.; Berkley (Mich.)--Churches.; Big Rapids (Mich.)--Churches.; Birch Run (Mich.)--Churches.; Birmingham (Mich.)--Churches.; Bloomfield Hills (Mich.)--Churches.; Brady (Saginaw County, Mich.: Township)--Churches.; Bridgeport (Mich.)--Churches.; Brown City (Mich.)--Churches.; Building dedications.; Cadillac (Mich.)--Churches.; Camps.; Capac (Mich.)--Churches.; Caro (Mich.)--Churches.; Carrollton (Mich.)--Churches.; Chelsea (Mich.)--Churches.; Chesaning (Mich.)--Churches.; Churches--Michigan.; Clarkston (Mich.)--Churches.; Clawson (Mich.)--Churches.; Clergy.; Clio (Mich.)--Churches.; Constantine (Mich.)--Churches.; Davison (Mich.)--Churches.; Dearborn (Mich.)--Churches.; Detroit (Mich.)--Churches.; Dexter (Mich.)--Churches.; Disco (Mich.)--Churches.; Drayton Plains (Mich.)--Churches.; Dundee (Mich.)--Churches.; Durand (Mich.)--Churches.; Eastpointe (Mich.)--Churches.; East Lansing (Mich.)--Churches.; East Tawas (Mich.)--Churches.; Essexville (Mich.)--Churches.; Fairgrove (Mich.)--Churches.; Farmington (Mich.)--Churches.; Fenton (Mich.)--Churches.; Ferndale (Mich.)--Churches.; Flint (Mich.)--Churches.; Flushing (Mich.)--Churches.; Fowlerville (Mich.)--Churches.; Frankenlust (Mich.)--Churches.; Frankenmuth (Mich.)--Churches.; Frankentrost (Mich.)--Churches.; Freedom (Mich.: Township)--Churches.; Freeland (Mich.)--Churches.; Germania (Mich.)--Churches.; Gladwin (Mich.)--Churches.; Glennie (Mich.)--Churches.; Gowen (Mich.)--Churches.; Grand Blanc (Mich.)--Churches.; Grand Ledge (Mich.)--Churches.; Grand Rapids (Mich.)--Churches.; Grayling (Mich.)--Churches.; Greenville (Mich.)--Churches.; Grosse Pointe Farms (Mich.)--Churches.; Grosse Pointe Woods (Mich.)--Churches.; Hadley (Mich.)--Churches.; Hale (Mich.)--Churches.; Hamburg (Mich.)--Churches.; Hamtramck (Mich.)--Churches.; Hazel Park (Mich.)--Churches.; Hemlock (Mich.)--Churches.; Highland (Mich.)--Churches.; Highland Park (Mich.)--Churches.; Holly (Mich.)--Churches.; Howell (Mich.)--Churches.; Illinois--Churches.; Imlay City (Mich.)--Churches.; Interiors.; Ionia (Mich.)--Churches.; Ira (Mich.)--Churches.; Ironwood (Mich.)--Churches.; Jackson (Mich.)--Churches.; Juhl (Mich.)--Churches.; Kalamazoo (Mich.)--Churches.; Kawkawlin (Mich.)--Churches.; Kent City (Mich.)--Churches.; Lake City (Mich.)--Churches.; Lake Orion (Mich.)--Churches.; Lansing (Mich.)--Churches.; Lapeer (Mich.)--Churches.; Le Roy (Mich.)--Churches.; Linkville (Mich.)--Churches.; Livonia (Mich.)--Churches.; Ludington (Mich.)--Churches.; Lutheran Church in America--Missions--Michigan.Michigan.Missions; Lutheran Church in America. Michigan Synod.; Macomb (Mich.)--Churches.; Madison Heights (Mich.)--Churches.; Manistee (Mich.)--Churches.; Marine City (Mich.)--Churches.; Marlette (Mich.)--Churches.; Marshall (Mich.)--Churches.; Marysville (Mich.)--Churches.; Mason (Mich.)--Churches.; Mayville (Mich.)--Churches.; Midland (Mich.)--Churches.; Milford (Mich.)--Churches.; Millington (Mich.)--Churches.; Missions--Michigan.; Monitor (Mich.: Township)--Churches.; Monroe (Mich.)--Churches.; Montcalm County (Mich.)--Churches.; Monuments and memorials--Michigan--Mount Clemens.; Mount Clements (Mich.)--Churches.; Mount Pleasant (Mich.)--Churches.; Munger (Mich.)--Churches.; Muskegon (Mich.)--Churches.; New Baltimore (Mich.)--Churches.; New Haven (Mich.)--Churches.; Niles (Mich.)--Churches.; North Branch (Mich.)--Churches.; Northville (Mich.)--Churches.; Ohio--Churches.; Okemos (Mich.)--Churches.; Orchard Lake (Mich.)--Churches.; Oscoda (Mich.)--Churches.; Ossineke (Mich.)--Churches.; Owosso (Mich.)--Churches.; Oxford (Mich.)--Churches.; Palmyra (Mich.)--Churches.; Pigeon (Mich.)--Churches.; Pinconning (Mich.)--Churches.; Pontiac (Mich.)--Churches.; Port Huron (Mich.)--Churches.; Portage (Mich.)--Churches.; Rankin (Mich.)--Churches.; Redford (Mich.: Township)--Churches.; Reese (Mich.)--Churches.; Religious services.; Rhodes (Mich.)--Churches.; Richmond (Mich.)--Churches.; Richville (Mich.)--Churches.; River Rouge (Mich.)--Churches.; Rochester (Mich.)--Churches.; Romeo (Mich.)--Churches.; Roscommon (Mich.)--Churches.; Roseville (Mich.)--Churches.; Royal Oak (Mich.)--Churches.; Saginaw (Mich.)--Churches.; Saint Clair (Mich.)--Churches.; Saint Clair Shores (Mich.)--Churches.; Saint Johns (Mich.)--Churches.; Saint Louis (Mich.)--Churches.; Sanford (Mich.)--Churches.; Sebawaing (Mich.)--Churches.; Shelby (Macomb County, Mich.: Township)--Churches.; South Lyon (Mich.)--Churches.; Southfield (Mich.)--Churches.; Southgate (Mich.)--Churches.; Squaconning Creek (Mich.)--Churches.; Standish (Mich.)--Churches.; Sterling (Mich.)--Churches.; Sterling Heights (Mich.)--Churches.; Swan Creek (Mich.)--Churches.; Swartz Creek (Mich.)--Churches.; Tawas City (Mich.)--Churches.; Taylor (Mich.)--Churches.; Tecumseh (Mich.)--Churches.; Temperance (Mich.)--Churches.; Three Rivers (Mich.)--Churches.; Trverse City (Mich.)--Churches.; Troy (Mich.)--Churches.; Trufant (Mich.)--Churches.; Tustin (Mich.)--Churches.; Utica (Mich.)--Churches.; Vassar (Mich.)--Churches.; Waldenburg (Mich.)--Churches.; Walled Lake (Mich.)--Churches.; Warren (Mich.)--Churches.; Washington (Mich.)--Churches.; Waterford (Mich.)--Churches.; Wayne (Mich.)--Churches.; West Branch (Mich.)--Churches.; Wheeler (Mich.)--Churches.; Williamston (Mich.)--Churches.; Woodland (Mich.)--Churches.; Wyoming (Mich.)--Churches.; Ypsilanti (Mich.)--Churches.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Organizational and Administrative Records
  The Organizational and Administrative Records series includes president's correspondence, executive committee minutes, minutes of the Synod's annual convention, and records from the organization and constituting conventions of the Michigan Synod in 1962.
  - President's correspondence (by date)
    - 1939-1951 (Box 1)
    - 1952-1964 (Box 2)
  - President's correspondence (by topic)
    - Indiana Synod (Box 2)
    - Wittenberg-Chicago campaign (Box 2)
    - Mulberry Home (Box 2)
    - Social missions and social action, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
    - Synod convention, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Constitution and By-laws (Box 3)
  - Executive Committee minutes, 1934-1987
    - 1934-1964 (Box 3)
    - 1965-1972 (Box 40)
    - 1973-1982 (Box 41)
    - 1983-1987 (Box 42)
    - Minutes of Michigan Synod Annual Conventions, 1917-1933 (Box 42)
    - Minutes of Michigan Synod Annual Conventions, 1934-1986 (Box 4)
      (lacks 1937 and 1978-1979, 1982 1985)
  - Organization and constituting convention of the Michigan Synod, 1962 (Box 5)
    (with background information and published material)
- Archivist's files, Michigan Synod
  The Archivist's files is a smaller series of collected materials on individual churches within the Synod, various reports, and other materials considered to be of historical importance.
  - Publications of individual churches, national publications, convention miscellanea, reports, etc., 1953-1974 (Box 6)
- Organizational Units and Programs
  The records of various Organizational Units and Programs within the Synod have been grouped together. This series includes minutes of the meetings of the Eastern and Western Conference of the Michigan Synod, minutes of the United Lutheran Pastor's Association, minutes of the Luther League, and records from the Gun Lake Summer Camp program. This series also contains extensive material on the Joint Commission on Lutheran Unity and files detailing the missions and social services activities of the Synod.
  - Minutes of meetings of Eastern and Western Conferences (Michigan Synod), 1944-1961 (Box 7)
  - Minutes and Record General of the Western Conference (Michigan Synod), 1944-1963 (Box 7)
  - Minutes of United Lutheran Pastor's Association, 1924-1944 (Box 7)
  - Luther League, minutes of executive meetings and conventions, 1942-1962 (Box 7)
  - Gun Lake Summer Camp files (Box 8)
  - Gun Lake Summer Camp files (Box 9)
  - Department of Research and Church Planning files (Box 9)
  - Detroit General Committee meetings (Box 9)
  - Missions and Social Services files (Box 10)
  - Notebooks concerning Lutheran schools and seminaries (Box 11)
  - Notebooks concerning the Counsel of Synodical Presidents (Box 11)
  - Notebooks concerning the Lutheran Church in the United States (Box 11)
  - Notebooks concerning the Joint Commission on Lutheran Unity (Box 13)
  - Notebooks concerning the Joint Commission on Lutheran Unity (Box 14)
  - Notebooks concerning the Michigan Joint Committee on Lutheran Unity (Box 15)
- Lutheran Church Women
  The Lutheran Church Women records cover the years 1961 to 1973, beginning with the planning and foundation of the organization, but ending abruptly twelve years later. While the bulk of the series pertains specifically to the Michigan Synod of the LCA, there is also some material pertaining to LCW on the national level.
  The national files includes minutes and other material from the Constituting Convention of the organization and the Leadership Training Session which immediately followed the convention. The LCW Guide contains information on the history, purpose and structure of the organization.
  The Michigan Synod LCW records include agendas and minutes of the Executive Board Meetings covering the years 1962-1973. These are a good source of information on the administration and basic functions of the organization. Minutes include regular reports from the treasurer outlining the financial management of the LCW, as well as periodic reports from the standing committees. The LCW annual conventions files begin with the Constituting Convention in 1962 and end in 1973. The conventions files are an excellent source for summary information on the aims and activities of the LCW. While these files usually include the program and minutes for each year, the folders for the conventions from 1967 to 1970 are particularly rich, including committee reports, minutes of the convention, summary evaluations of the conventions and budgeting and planning information.
  - History of Women's Missionary Society (name changed in 1955 to United Lutheran Church Women) (Box 36)
  - Women's Missionary Society, Minutes of conventions and other printed material (Box 36)
  - Lutheran Church in America (Box 36)
  - Newsletters (many issues missing), 1964-1970 (Box 36)
  - National Organization (LCW)
    - Constituting Convention, 1962 (Box 36)
    - Leadership Training Session, Constituting Convention, 1962 (Box 36)
    - LCW Guide (Box 36)
  - Michigan Synod (LCW:MS)
    - Executive Board Meetings-Agendas (Box 36)
    - Executive Board Meetings-Minutes, 1962-1973; 6 folders (Box 36)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1966-1971 (Box 36)
    - Committee Reports
      - Joint Planning Committee, 1961-1962 (Box 36)
      - Miscellaneous Reports, 1971 (Box 36)
    - Correspondence (selected), 1963; 1965-1970 (Box 36)
    - Constitution (Box 36)
    - Conventions
      - Constituting Convention, 1962 (Box 36)
      - Conventions, 1963-1973; 11 folders (Box 36)
    - District Assemblies, 1963-1970 (Box 37)
    - Activities
      - Volunteer Reading Aids, 1969-1970 (Box 37)